michael/smith

michael@eightnine.co / eightnine.co/smith / (404) 661-6558

Professional Focus

As a front-end developer working out of Chicago I've spent the past five years focusing on architecting & building complex, eye-catching, and scalable React + Redux web apps for a wide variety of clients. I utilize my strong background in visual and interaction design in all my development projects, making sure that the solutions I implement are grounded by time tested UX concepts and meet the accessibility needs of all my clients' users. Having spent years working in the React + Redux stack, I've begun expanding into more experimental web features such as service workers and client-side AR as well as competing technology like Vue JS.

Experience

Senior Interactive Developer

2017 — Current

Isobar — Chicago, IL

As a senior developer with Isobar, I've focused primarily on building React + Redux web applications for the United States Air Force and within the Enterprise flagship site. I've architected and lead numerous smaller projects and feature releases for both clients, and worked seamlessly within larger teams for more significant releases and milestones.

Senior UI Developer

2014 - 2017

Dunn Solutions Group — Skokie, IL

As a senior UI Developer at Dunn Solutions Group I built a wide variety of dynamic, fully responsive portals & e-commerce sites for clients that ranged from global cosmetic companies to hospital chains. I led the front-end development & UI design efforts for many of these projects from inception to completion, working directly with our clients.

Graphic Designer

2013 - 2014

DePaul University's AMD Department — Chicago, IL

As the AMD Department's in house graphic designer I created two identity systems for DePaul's annual art showcases, The I AM I Showcase and the 2014 Senior Capstone Exhibition. Additionally, I designed a wide variety of posters, promotional materials and installation graphics for the AMD Department's faculty and professors.

Education

DePaul University

2014

Chicago, IL

Bachelor's Degree in Interactive Media — Concentration in Interaction Design